# DANIEL .UDOKA. OGBUIGWE

| (+234) 806-430-8353 | ogbuigwed@gmail.com |

A23, Road 2, Victoria Garden City, Lagos, Nigeria | LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-ogbuigwe-620286200/

#### PROFILE

An AWS certified cloud practitioner with experience in mechanical engineering and network operations. Monitoring shared communication infrastructure used by local telecom giants like MTN and Airtel fostered my interest in large scale systems and cloud technology. Coupled with the recent boom in AI awareness globally, I have genuine interest in making future systems more accessible to developing economies.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor (B.Eng) | Mechanical Engineering | Baze University, Abuja

Sept. 2016 – Aug. 2021

Key Courses Taken: Engineering Mathematics, Thermodynamics, Manufacturing and Industrial Quality Control

# Post-Graduate Diploma (PGD) | Computer Science | Babcock University, Ilishan-Remo Dec 2023

Jan. 2023

• Key Courses Taken: Computing Systems, Database Systems, Quantitative Methods, Programming Techniques, Data Structures and Algorithms, Introduction to Artificial Intelligence.

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

# Undergraduate Dissertation | Baze University, Abuja

Sept 2016. - Aug. 2021

Contributors: Mr. Irana Biradar, supervisor

Assembled a 3D printer using Fused Deposition Modelling technology following the Tronxy Manufactureing blueprint

### Post Graduate Diploma Paper | Babcock University, Ilishan

Jan. - Dec. 2023

Contributors: Dr Nzenwata Jerry, supervisor | On-going

- Advancing Speech Recognition and Synthesis for the Ika Language (Working Paper Title).
- Worked with native speakers to curate a 1hr+ labelled speech dataset of Ika readings.
- Adapter fine-tuned the MMS-300M model from Meta on Hugging Face platform with the Ika readings dataset to improve performance on ASR and Speech synthesis tasks.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Back Office Engineer Intern| Huawei Technologies Company Nigeria Limited, Lagos

May 2022 - Feb 2023

Network operations surveillance for MTN

2022 - Now

- Escalating service outages and recording all forms of service downtime for eastern Nigeria region.
- While on the team, we maintained a 98+% service uptime.

### Network Operations Center Engineer Intern | I-engineering Nigeria Limited, Lagos

Dec. 2021 – May 2022

- Monitor the operations of various telecommunication towers including power and environmental alarms, and minimizing site
  down times
- Generate incident reports, troubleshoot and respond to incidents on the systems, communicate with site technicians or third parties responsible for resolution and performing root-cause analysis
- I successfully resolved an average of 3 to 5 incident alarms daily for my assigned regions.

#### **Undergrad Internship Experiences (M.Eng) | Various Companies |**

June 2018 - Dec 2019

I undertook multiple internships during my undergraduate studies. As a Junior Mechanic at **Coscharis Motors**, I contributed to vehicle repairs and maintenance. At **Cakasa NIG Company LTD**, I was assigned to the Quality Control team during the LPG tank construction project. As a Logistics Intern at **Strides Energy & Maritime LTD**, I efficiently managed construction materials logistics and inventory control for Niger-Delta riverine development projects. These diverse roles enhanced my practical understanding and adaptability in various work environments..

# LEADERSHIP AND NON-ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

Volunteer Instructor | Accord for Development, (Lagos State Employment Trust Fund & USADF), Lagos

Dec.

Teaching assistant. Class focus: Basic IT, Google Suite, Adobe Creative Suite, Autodesk Maya. Handled logistics tasks.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS & OTHERS**

**Computer Skills:** AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (Issued: Oct 23, 2023); AWS Solutions Architect Associate Pending Exam; Python, Git.